## Dear Authorized,

After finishing my mechanical engineering education in 2016, I performed my profession as an engineer for a while. Afterwards, I had a long process to participate in the pilot training program of an airline company.

My education life provided me with the necessary infrastructure for your position. Besides, I have improved myself in organizational skills, analytical thinking, research, motivation, entrepreneurship or acquiring different skills thanks to the club activities I have done throughout my school life. As you can see in my resume, I prepared myself with the trainings I received and the research I did.

I participated in the Qualified Informatics Expert Training Program, organized jointly by the Bilge Adam Informatics Group and the Ministry of Labor. I learned Web and Mobile Programming under this program.

I would like to state that I want to take the responsibility required by the position on me, thanks to my ability to learn and adapt easily in my educational life. As both an analytical thinking perfectionist and an individual who respects demands and is prone to teamwork I think I can contribute to you with my talents and discipline.

While I am looking forward to your valuable returns, I invite you to review my CV in more detail.

Best Regards,

Osman Şahin

# OSMAN ŞAHİN

## **Full Stack Developer**

**Phone** : +90 (536) 353-6869

**Phone-2** : +90 (533) 355-7313 (Ali ŞAHİN)

E-Mail : osmansahin.eng@gmail.com , contact@osahin.net

LinkedIn : https://www.linkedin.com/in/o-sahin/en

GitHub: https://github.com/osman-sahin

Website : <a href="https://osahin.net">https://osahin.net</a>



#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of Birth : 20 Aug 1987 Driving License : B (2006)

Place of Birth : Izmir, Turkey Military Status : Paid (2015)

**EDUCATION** 

06/2020 Bilge Adam Technologies (%100 Scholarship) Ankara, Turkey

NBUY(Training Qualified IT Experts) Programme by ISKUR / 800 Hours

10/2016 Yıldız Technical University Istanbul, Turkey

**Mechanical Engineering** 

**EXPERIENCES** 

08/2020 – 01/2020 **HaydeSoft – Full Stack Developer**(*Remote*) Ankara, Türkiye

In this team, where we work as "Remote" upon the demands of the customers, including the Presidency of the Republic of Turkey; I worked as the only Full Stack Developer of the team in the development of web applications using the following technologies, methodologies and frameworks.

-Angular -MS SQL -Agile -SyncFusion
-.NET Core -PostgreSQL -Scrum -PrimeNG

12/2019 – 06/2020 Bilge Adam Technologies – Software Developer Ankara, Turkey

Web and Mobile Programming Course at Bilge Adam Academy that belongs to Bilge Adam Technologies which is supported by ISKUR that is an organization of the Ministry of Labor and Social Security within NBUY(Training Qualified IT Experts) programme. During the course i developed projects by using

following technologies and principles;

C#, .Net Framework, .Net Core, OOP, .NET MVC, Web API, Entity Framework, Microsoft SQL Server, ADO.NET, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, JavaScript, JQuery, Ajax, AngularJS, Git, CORS, Dependency

Injection, SOLID Principles and Design Patterns

#### 10/2019-11/2019

## **Akat Environmental Technologies- Sales Engineer**

Istanbul, Turkey

- To conduct customer relations
- To organize product service providing onsite,
- To conduct market research.

#### 02/2017-08/2017

#### HABAŞ Iron & Steel - Mechanical Maintenance Engineer

Izmir, Turkey

- Preparing CPM reports as an engineer in charge of Crane Maintenance Unit in Machinery Maintenance Department.
- To coordinate my team in the planned and unplanned maintenance process,
- Performing visual inspection of cranes,
- Following the inventory of the unit and following the purchases and orders through SAP,
- To ensure the installation of new cranes produced within the scope of the expansion of the factory, the production follow-up of the cranes being produced and the necessary revisions to be made..

06/2016-08/2016

## **Metrosan Biomedical Devices**

Manisa, Turkey

Mechanical Design (Internship - 20 days) / Management (Internship - 20 days)

• Participating in R&D studies

02/2016-03/2016

## Özköseoğlu Heat Industry Production (Internship - 20 days)

Istanbul, Turkey

Observing production processes and perform time optimization study

#### **CERTIFICATES**

01/2021	Front-End JavaScript Frameworks: Angular / The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology
	https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/YMZCN6DLMGCC
06/2020	Exam 70-480: Programming in HTML5 with JavaScript and CSS3 / Microsoft
	https://www.youracclaim.com/badges/c9a261c5-975c-4c1c-a28a-85a0a5b1b87a
06/2020	NBUY Programme Certificate: Software Developer / Ministry of Education
06/2020	Certificate of Participation: Software Developer / Bilge Adam Technologies
05/2020	Certificate of Completion: ASP.NET Core Fundamentals / Pluralsight (Online)
05/2020	Certificate of Completion: Building Web Applications with ASP.NET Core MVC / Pluralsight (Online)
05/2020	Certificate of Completion: Building an API with ASP.NET Core / Pluralsight (Online)
05/2020	Certificate of Completion: Dependency Injection in ASP.NET Core / Pluralsight (Online)
09/2017	IELTS - Academic: Overall Band Score: 6 / British Council
08/2010	Certificate of Completion: High-Intermediate / Sprachcaffe Languages Plus - Brighton, UK
08/2009	Certificate of Completion: Intermediate / Tti School of English - London, UK

# **PROJECTS**

	Individually;		
06/2020	Enterprise Website that has Customer Portal for a Financial Advisor	https://smmm.osahin.net/	
	- C#, .NET Core MVC, Identity, MSSQL, EF Core, Dependency Injection, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery		
06/2020	Gallery Website that has Administration Portal for a Painter	https://kraft.osahin.net/	
	- C#, .NET Core MVC, Identity, MSSQL, EF Core, Dependency Injection, HTML5, CSS3, JQuery		
	Within the scope of education in Bilge Adam Academy;		
01/2020	Snake Game – C#, Windows Form		
02/2020	KafeKod – Cafe Order Management Programme – C#, Windows Form		
04/2020	ChatBOB – Online Chat Application – .NET Framework MVC, JQuery	https://chat.osahin.net/	
05/2020	Personal Blog with Admin Panel – .NET Framework MVC, Identity, JQuery	https://blog.osahin.net/	
05/2020	SPA Note App. – .NET Framework, WebAPI, AngularJs, Identity, MSSQL	https://note.osahin.net/	
06/2020	E-Shop (ongoing) – .NET Core MVC, Clean Architecture Layers, Identity, EF Core, MSSQL		
	Within the scope of education in Yıldız Technical University;		
10/2015-01/2016	Centrifugal Pump (Mechanical Design Project)		
10/2015-01/2016	Portable PV(Photovoltaic) Power Generator (Mechanical Design Project)		
02/2015-06/2016	Double-Girder Overhead Crane (Graduation Thesis)		

# **LANGUAGES**

• English B2/C1 (Advanced)

• Turkish Native

# **COMPUTER SKILLS**

C#

ASP.NET / ASP.NET Core

ASP.NET MVC

Microsoft SQL Server

OOP

Web API

Entity Framework

Angular 2+

• HTML5

• CSS3

JavaScript

Bootstrap

Jquery

AngularJS

T-SQL

PostgreSQL

AJAX

ADO.NET

SOLID

• Git

Microsoft Office

SolidWorks

AutoCAD

# **HOBBIES**

• Travelling, Paragliding, Rock Climbing, Listening Music, Fishing

# REFERENCES

- **Yiğit HACIEFENDİOĞLU** Instructor Bilge Adam Technologies +90 (0505) 839-5568 yiğit.haciefendioğlu@bilgeadam.com
- **Aynur UZMAN** Financial Advisor +90 (0555) 246-4601
- **Serdar KAYA** Founder, Senior Full Stack Developer Haydesoft +90 (506) 860-1331 serdar@haydesoft.com
- Emin GÖKKURT Painter +90 (536) 388-1937 - info@kraftresim.com